<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>East India Cycling </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on East India Cycling </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling Holidays in Northeast India</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>East India Cycle Tours is an initiative of North by Northeast Journeys  and as the name suggests we offers bicycling holidays in the northeastern region of India. A pioneer of cycling tours in the east of India we have for a decade now been offering unique getaways in this beautiful region of the sub-continent.
A tough mountain bike expedition on some of the highest roads of the eastern Himalayas, an exciting cycle traverse across the forested tracts of the tribal hills or an easier cycling tour in the lush valleys of Assam, we have it all covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Assam </title>
      <link>/cycling-in-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-assam/</guid>
      <description>Cycle tour of Assam: Cycling the physical heart of Northeastern India This cycle tour takes you along the length of the Brahmaputra River, across Assam. This is the physical heart of Northeast India, a verdant region fed by a network of mighty rivers coming down from the mountains on three sides. As the tour progresses you will interact and observe diverse cultures. Starting from Guwahati at the heart of the Brahmaputra Valley you will come across the settled and relatively more sophisticated people of the plains including the Assamese, Bodo and Mishing in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>Cycling in Meghalaya: The Khasi and Jaintia hills On this bicycle tour of Meghalaya we will be riding through the west Khasi and neighbouring Jaintia hills overlooking the plains of Bangladesh. All the while riding across deep forested valleys, gushing rivers, innumerable waterfalls, observing archery competitions, village markets and visiting quaint villages. We also include a day hike so as not to miss out the wonders that are the living root bridges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-eastern-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-eastern-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>Cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh: Explore the mouth of the Brahmaputra Valley This cycle tour of Eastern Arunachal Pradesh (the eastern most state of India) takes you to the watershed of the mighty Brahmaputra River. This is where the three easternmost tributaries come together to form one of the mightiest river valleys of the world.
Exciting experiences right from crossing one of the largest rivers of India in Assam to cycling through the riverine areas of the Siang, Dibang and the Lohit Rivers of eastern Arunachal Pradesh, all the while overshadowed by the mighty Himalayan chain .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>Cycle Tour of Western Arunachal Pradesh: The Himalayan High This cycle tour of western Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the periphery of beautiful Tawang. The setting of this ride of Arunachal Pradesh is in the Buddhist belt home to the Monpa, Brokpa and Sherdukpen people close to the border with Bhutan and Tibet. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in The Mishmi Hills of Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-mishmi-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-mishmi-hills/</guid>
      <description>Cycling in the Mishmi Hills of Arunachal Pradesh: Himalaya’s eastern flank The cycle tour of Mishmi Hills takes you to the far eastern flank of the Himalayas, this is where the mighty Himalayan chain ends (or starts). Lying in the eastern Arunachal Pradesh, the Mishmi hills is an untouched wonderland of undending swathes of prestine nature. This is home to the animist Mishmi tribes, some of the smallest linguistic groups of the subcontinent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hike, Cycle, Raft, Culture in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>Hike, Bike, Raft and Culture tour of Arunachal Pradesh: Eastern Arunachal unravelled This multi-activity tour of eastern Arunachal Pradesh takes us on bicycles, rafts and on foot across the watershed area of the Brahmaputra River valley. This region situated at the foothills of the Mishmi hills the eastern flank to the Himalayan chain, is the land of the Animist and Theravada Buddhist tribes.
Authentic interactions, local cuisine, history and lifestyle of the tribes etc are our focus here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure, Culture, Wildlife tour of Assam</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-assam/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Activity Holiday in Assam: Adventure, Culture and wildlife in the Brahmaputra valley This multi-activity tour takes us to the Brahmaputra valley of Assam. A lush strip of land sandwiched between the Himalayan landmass on the north and the lesser hills of Nagaland and Meghalaya in the south. The Brahmaputra valley is home to a multitude of ethinicities, a string of wildlife sanctuaries and the famous Assam tea among others.
On this tour we will indulge in short day ride, walking forays, elephant &amp;amp; jeep safari&amp;rsquo;s, tea plantation &amp;amp; factory visits, explore the culture and cuisine of this land,spot the endangered River Dolphins of the Brahmaputra, cycle around the largest river island of the world while staying in live in Tea bungalows, Safari lodges and Eco camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hike, Cycle, Culture holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>MULTI-ACTIVITY HOLIDAY IN MEGHALAYA: HIKE, BIKE, CULTURE IN THE &amp;lsquo;ABODE OF CLOUDS&amp;rsquo; This particular Multi-activity tour takes us on bicycles and on foot across the Khasi and Jaintia Hills of Meghalaya. Due to its unique georgaphical location, it some of the highest rain fall on earth which in turn bestows this region with its amazing mix of forested valleys and grassland plateaus.
The cycling phase takes you across the beautiful landscape, whereas the hiking days take you through some of the best trails of the region, amongst which the famous living root bridges trail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Sikkim &amp; West Bengal</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-sikkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-sikkim/</guid>
      <description>Cycle Tour of Sikkim &amp;amp; W Bengal: Of Mountains and Monastries This tour of Sikkim takes us through East, South and Western districts of this beautiful himalayan state. We will generally be in sub alpine rural himalayas, this provides us an excellent opportunity to observe life in these parts, interact with the locals and throughout be accompanied by amazing panoramas of the high himalayas. This tour takes you through most of the important locations of this state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trans-Meghalaya Cycling Tour</title>
      <link>/trans-meghalaya-cycling-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/trans-meghalaya-cycling-tour/</guid>
      <description>Cycle Tour of Meghalaya: Cycling the Garo, Khasi and Jaintia hills The Trans Meghalaya cycling tour takes you across the three hill ranges of the state. Starting from the west in the Garo Hills, we ride eastewards across the Khasi and Jaintia hills, in essence taking in the best that the state has to offer. The state of Meghalaya is the first line of hills that the Monsoon clouds touch upon crossing peninsular India, hence it receives some of the highest rainfall anywhere on earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>