<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>East India Cycling </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on East India Cycling </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling Holidays in Northeast India</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-northeast-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-northeast-india/</guid>
      <description>East India Cycle Tours is an initiative of North by Northeast Journeys  and as the name suggests we offers bicycling holidays in the northeastern region of India. A pioneer of cycling tours in the east of India we have for a decade now been offering unique getaways in this beautiful region of the sub-continent.
A tough mountain bike expedition on some of the highest roads of the eastern Himalayas, an exciting cycle traverse across the forested tracts of the tribal hills or an easier cycling tour in the lush valleys of Assam, we have it all covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Assam </title>
      <link>/cycling-in-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-assam/</guid>
      <description>Sprawled along the length of the Brahmaputra valley, Assam is the biggest and most accessible of the Northeast States. A hospitable population, a cuisine with its own distinctive aromas and flavours, a vibrant artistic heritage marked by exotic dance forms, and a string of Wildlife Sanctuaries top its list of innumerable attractions. The archetypal Assamese landscape is a picturesque golden-green vista of rice fields and manicured tea estates, framed by the blue mountains of Arunachal Pradesh in the north and the highlands of Meghalaya and Nagaland to the south.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>Separating the Brahmaputra valley from the plains of Bangladesh, hilly Meghalaya – the ‘abode of clouds’ – is a cool, pine-fresh mountain state set on dramatic horseshoes of rocky cliffs. Cherrapunjee and Mawsynram are statistically among the wettest places on Earth; most of the rain falls between June and September known as the Monsoons, creating very impressive waterfalls and carving out some of Asia’s longest caves. Meghalaya is also home to the only matri-lineal society of the eastern region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Eastern Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-eastern-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-eastern-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>This is a fairly awesome cycle tour in Arunachal Pradesh, the eastern most state of India. Exciting experiences right from crossing one of the largest rivers in India at Dibrugarh to cycling through the riverine areas of the Siang and the Dibang Rivers of eastern Arunachal Pradesh . This bicycle tour offers bounties of wide vistas, little known villages, myriads of ethnic groups and some of the better wildlife sanctuaries of the subcontinent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Western Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-western-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-western-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>This cycle tour of western Arunachal Pradesh takes you all the way to the periphery of beautiful Tawang. The setting of this ride of Arunachal Pradesh is in the Buddhist belt home to the Monpa and Sherdukpen people close to the border with Bhutan and Tibet. This is one of the highest motorable routes of the eastern bit of the Himalayas, at places taking you to an altitude of 4200mts. The road condition though not at the best is still better than most parts of Arunachal Pradesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in The Mishmi Hills of Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/cycling-mishmi-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-mishmi-hills/</guid>
      <description>This particular cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes us from the Namdapha National Park to the Acheso Valley which is where the road ends (If there were a road we would end up in China). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hike, Bike, Raft, Culture in Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-arunachal-pradesh/</guid>
      <description>This particular cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes us from the Namdapha National Park to the Acheso Valley which is where the road ends (If there were a road we would end up in China). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure, Culture, Wildlife tour of Assam</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-assam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-assam/</guid>
      <description>This particular cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes us from the Namdapha National Park to the Acheso Valley which is where the road ends (If there were a road we would end up in China). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hike, Bike, Culture holiday in Meghalaya</title>
      <link>/multi-activity-holiday-meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multi-activity-holiday-meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>This particular cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes us from the Namdapha National Park to the Acheso Valley which is where the road ends (If there were a road we would end up in China). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Sikkim &amp; West Bengal</title>
      <link>/cycling-in-sikkim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cycling-in-sikkim/</guid>
      <description>This tour of Sikkim takes us through East, South and Western districts of this beautiful himalayan state. We will generally be in sub alpine rural himalayas, this provides us an excellent opportunity to observe life in these parts, interact with the locals and throughout be accompanied by amazing panoramas of the high himalayas. This tour takes you through most of the important locations of this state.
overview  Level: Tough Total Days: 9 to 14 Max.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trans-Meghalaya Cycling Tour</title>
      <link>/trans-meghalaya-cycling-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/trans-meghalaya-cycling-tour/</guid>
      <description>This particular cycle tour of Arunachal Pradesh takes us from the Namdapha National Park to the Acheso Valley which is where the road ends (If there were a road we would end up in China). In between the start and the end, one will traverse across varied landscape, terrain, road conditions and meet the all important tribes of this region. From the tropical forests of Namdapha and Kamlang to the cane and grasslands of the Acheso valley, everyday is a revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>